Ahmet OZKESEK

17 Stonor Road Ground Floor Flat West Kensington W14 8RZ LONDON

M: 0772 922 3112

E: aozkesek@gmail.com

Summary

I am 25+ years experienced Software Developer/Programmer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering. I developed, planned and designed various software for Contact Centre, ATM Management, Document Management and Workflow Management. I worked 16 years in Banking and Financial sector in Istanbul-Turkey. Now, I would like to take job things easy again, and I am seeking a mid-level Java Programmer role in London where I can continue to improve myself first in English Language and Culture then programming.

Experience

Oct 2016 – date Istanbul, London Freelancer	
---	--

- Chose voluntarily to be unemployed and focused myself,
- Self studying Java EE, AWS, Document DB/NoSQL
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-809 OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (81%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-ocp.pdf
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-808 OCA lava 8 SE Programmer I (94%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-oca.pdf
- Designing and developing an Android Video Chat Application https://github.com/aozkesek/p2p-cast
- Designed and developed a Hospital Management Software with Biometric Verification for ZieZix360 from Nigeria. It was a Proof of Concept application that contains a Fingerprint and a Camera reader service module, multiple web service modules, and a web UI module. https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm

http://ziezix360.com/about-us/

Developed a group of PoC applications for an e-commerce web site and it's test automations

https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner

Jul 2014 - Aug 2016	NETAS, Istanbul	Consultant
---------------------	-----------------	------------

- Designed some services and wrote their Technical Design Document for companies that use Cisco Unified Communication and IP Desktop Phones.
- Created a prototype of IP Phone Service to join AVAYA Developer Connect Program

https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program_benefits/overview/ index.gsp

https://downloads.avaya.com/css/P8/documents/101026461

Developed a web application for managing a group of Cisco IP Phone Services https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager

https://github.com/aozkesek/license-manager

Trained the junior team members

	Nov 2001 - Jan 2014	Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul	Senior Programmer
--	---------------------	---------------------------	-------------------

- Led a Workflow Management Development team for 3 months
- Developed and maintained workflow and document management service
- Developed and maintained automatic teller machine service
- Involved upgrading of contact centre infrastructure and hardware
- Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

Aug 1999 - Aug 2001	Demirbank, Istanbul	Programmer
---------------------	---------------------	------------

Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

Skills

- Still developing skills:
 - AWS (IAM, ...),
 - Document DB / NoSQL (Mongo, Redis, Cassandra)
- Java 8, JavaScript
- C#, C
- TDD: Junit, TestNG, Selenium
- Docker, Docker Compose
- Gradle, Maven, Git
- JEE: Spring Framework & Boot, Hibernate ORM, JSF & Primefaces
- ASP.NET, Entity Framework, PostSharp
- RDBMS: Oracle, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- JTAPI & Cisco, Genesys CTI & IVR

Education

University of Istanbul, 1990 – 1997, Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering (https://bilgisayarmuhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr/en/_)

Qualifications

- Pearson Vue, London, 2020: **OCP** Java 8 SE Programmer II, (1Z0-809, 81%) https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/73245c76-e69e-4d2f-9513-780e5e98aae8
- Pearson Vue, London, 2019: OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (1Z0-808, 94%)
- Genesys, Istanbul, 2010: Certified GVP (IP IVR) Developer Course
- Cisco, Istanbul, 2007: CUCM Cisco Unified Communication Manager Course
- Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul, 2005: JSP, MVC Apache Struts Course
- Genesys, San Fransisco, 2001: Genesys Certified CTI Developer Course
- Netron, Istanbul, 1999: ASP VBScript, COM VB & C++ Course